Now that you've seen the use of color and visuals,
الآن وبعد أن رأيتم كيفية استخدام اللون والمرئيات،
let's look at a few additional encodings.
فلنلقِ نظرة على بعض الترميزات الإضافية.
Sometimes you'll need additional encodings to distinguish data in a visual.
ستحتاج أحيانًا إلى ترميزات إضافية لتمييز البيانات في المرئيات.
For these cases, you might want to use different encoding such as shape or size.
بالنسبة إلى هذه الحالات، قد ترغب في استخدام ترميز مختلف مثل الشكل أو الحجم.
In a scatter plot,
في مخطط مبعثر،
we might change the size or shape of the markers.
قد نغير حجم أو شكل العلامات.
In this video, you will learn about some additional encodings.
في هذا الفيديو، ستتعرفون على بعض الترميزات الإضافية.
When you're making scatter plot,
عندما تقوم بعمل مخطط مبعثر،
you're representing the data with dots,
فإنك تمثل البيانات بنقاط،
or maybe some other symbol.
أو ربما باستخدام بعض الرموز الأخرى.
Here, we are comparing the average SAT scores for students at different universities.
هنا، نقوم بمقارنة متوسط درجات اختبار SAT للطلاب في الجامعات المختلفة.
Each point is the information of a single university.
كل نقطة هي معلومات جامعة بمفردها.
Right now, the visual encoding of the data is oppositional,
وحاليًا، يعد الترميز المرئي للبيانات أمرًا معارضًا،
only using the x and y axes.
لذلك استخدموا فقط المحورين x وy.
If these are the only two columns we want to encode,
إذا كان هذان هما العمودان الوحيدان اللذان نريد ترميزهما،
I can't imagine a visual that paints the relationship in a more clear way.
فلا يمكنني تخيل عنصر مرئي يرسم العلاقة بطريقة أكثر وضوحًا.
However, we could introduce
ومع ذلك، يمكننا تقديم
additional encodings to show additional features in our dataset.
ترميزات إضافية لعرض ميزات إضافية في مجموعة البيانات.
Say whether the school is private or public.
حدد ما إذا كانت المدرسة خاصة أو عامة.
Now, imagine we also want to understand
تخيل الآن أننا نريد أيضًا فهم
the student-faculty ratios associated with each school.
نسب الطلاب لهيئة التدريس المرتبطة بكل مدرسة.
We will need another encoding.
سنحتاج إلى ترميز آخر.
Even though we get a lot of information from the marker size,
على الرغم من حصولنا على الكثير من المعلومات من حجم العلامة،
it's not a very accurate representation.
إلا أنه لا يُعد تمثيلًا دقيقًا للغاية.
It can also be ambiguous as to how the size should be interpreted.
يمكن أن يكون أيضًا غامضًا حول كيفية تفسير الحجم.
Should the viewer be comparing the diameter of the marker or the area?
هل يجب أن يقارن المشاهد بين قطر العلامة أو المنطقة؟
Data can also be encoded using different shapes,
يمكن أيضًا ترميز البيانات باستخدام أشكال مختلفة،
but we don't encode quantitative data with shapes as we
ولكننا لا نقوم بترميز البيانات الكمية بالأشكال، لأننا
probably run out of the number of shapes to encode our values.
قد نستنفد عدد الأشكال المتاحة لترميز قيمنا.
You would instead need to change your data to a categorical ordinal variable,
ستحتاج بدلاً من ذلك إلى تغيير بياناتك إلى متغير ترتيبي فئوي،
and encoding quantitative data with color can be confusing.
كما أن ترميز البيانات الكمية بالألوان يمكن أن يكون مربكًا.
Look at this example.
انظروا إلى هذا المثال.
The shapes are not as great as color for differentiating the schools,
الأشكال ليست تميز المدارس بشكل كبير كالألوان،
and the colors here are hardly an indicator of all the different student-faculty ratios.
والألوان هنا بالكاد تشير إلى جميع نسب المختلفة بين الطلاب وهيئة التدريس.
In general, color and shape are best used for categorical variables,
وبشكل عام، يُفضل استخدام اللون والشكل للمتغيرات الفئوية،
while the size of the marker can assist in adding
بينما يمكن أن يساعد حجم العلامة في إضافة
additional quantitative data as we demonstrated here.
بيانات كمية إضافية كما أوضحنا هنا.
I personally try to avoid these types of encodings if possible.
وأنا شخصيًا أحاول تجنب هذه الأنواع من الترميزات، إن أمكن.
But sometimes these additional encodings are necessary.
لكن في بعض الأحيان تكون هذه الترميزات الإضافية ضرورية.
If you start to lose the message,
إذا بدأتم تفقدون الرسالة،
consider breaking your visual into more visuals that each conveys its own direct message.
ففكروا في تقسيم مرئياتكم إلى المزيد من المرئيات التي ينقل كل منها رسالته المباشرة.